アリと何ひとつ変わらない いや　それ以上に…
That two billion reward
per spider is attractive, but finding them will be impossible. Yeah...
運悪く爆死を免れた者の体内に 効率良く取り込まれ 迅速に内部を破壊すると同時に
Very x Sharp x Eye
被毒者の肉体が 毒そのものとなり
Gon and his friends are
pursuing the Phantom Troupe, and have now obtained the money
新たな毒を放出しながら やがて　死に至る
to buy the information they need.
その毒の量と死ぬまでの時間が 実に絶妙で
That's crazy... You actually have money.
大量の連鎖被毒者を 生み出せる点にあった
Man, you really pawned
your Hunter License?
要するに…
You're insane.
うっ！
So, what should we do first?
あっ…。
Let's start by purchasing
a Southernbees catalog.
この上なく非人道的な 悪魔兵器だったのである
Here is this year's
Southernbees auction catalog.
こ…　これは…
Remember how four-eyes mentioned that
私の身に　一体　何が？
really talented people use Nen without
even realizing it themselves?
プフ。
Wing-san. He taught us Nen.
いかがされました？　メルエム様。
If we search for items with
aura on them, like this knife, it's likely some genius made them. I get it!
もしや 考え直していただけましたか？
with no formal appraisal training. Then we auction the items at a higher price!
それならば　一刻も早く避難を。
If you guys want that,
write down your price.
王？
Customers are supposed to
name their own prices?
見え透いていてもなお
Yeah, that's how this market works.
決して自らは言わぬか まぁ　よい。 余が先に　残りの侵入者を 捕獲すれば済む話。
You write down what you're willing to pay, and when time expires,
the highest bidder wins the item. Understand? Popular items
お主の秘密 がぜん　興味が湧いて来た。
will see their prices shoot up.
洗いざらい話す旨　まさか ほごにする気はあるまいな？
I get it now.
この身　ちぎれても 約束は守りまする。
I'll check the online forums. Okay!
よかろう。
This is a weird pot, but I detect aura...
あと１回だけという 約束の「円」を　もう？
Even if you end up bidding too high,
you'll succeed in discouraging any rivals.
見える
500 multiplied by 2.5...
全て
Let's see...
前には　なかった足跡が
It's the same person!
乗り捨てられた車が
Same on your side?
ユピーの骸が
I found a couple items, but both had bids already placed by "Zepile."
閉まっていた扉が 新たに 余の「円」に反応した者も
And after I entered a bid 2.5 times higher, he multiplied that by 4. Then it isn't a coincidence?
ん!?
What should we do? Keep placing bids until the deadline.
なっ…!?
There are two of us, so we'll win some!
ユピーを仕留めたのは貴様か？
So ultimately, we won three and lost one.
と…　とんでもございません！
Yeah, he got that weird pot.
なぜ　師団長の私めが
Well, that wasn't too bad.
ユピー殿を　あやめる道理など ございましょうか？
Let's take these to the auction house now.
ユピー殿は
I am very sorry.
私めと話をしている最中に 突然　吐血し　苦しみだし 果てたのでございます！ 誓って　うそではございません！
But the auction house cannot
accept any additional items, once the catalog has been published. Isn't there any way?
これは　うそじゃ　ねえ！ 俺は… 俺は　確かにユピーを撃った
We really want to auction these.
だが
I suggest that you give
the trade market a try.
奴は俺の質問に答える前に…
The trade market?
俺の「クロムカデ」がかえる前に 苦しみだし くたばった
The trade market... Professionals will be here, so if one of these
is genuine, we should get a great price.
恐らく　私めと会う前に
I wanted to sell these at the auction, though. How much do you think we'll get?
すでに何らかの敵の攻撃を 受けていたのでございます！
Let's find out.
よって　私めは　賊が群衆に 紛れていないかを調べるため ここに来た次第でございます！
Oh, you found these in your cellar? Yep! Dad said to sell them if the price was right.
あっ…。
These are wonderful pieces.
クッ…　護衛軍プフ 厄介な奴が来やがった
Only fifty copies were printed, and yours has a single-digit serial number.
こいつには何か こっちの心を見透かす力がある
And an authentic autograph. We know.
この場で何を言いだすか 分からない
I'd guess it's worth at least 150,000.
きゃつは　口止めでは　ぬるい
This antique doll is also excellent...
できれば 今すぐにでも始末すべき 強引に　叛意ありと断罪し 処分する
It's in great shape, and the pristine condition of both
box and doll raises the value.
最悪でも　王から引き離さねば
I'm estimating 300,000. However, this one isn't worth much, unfortunately.
メルエム様　そ奴は…。
Huh?
「円」で触れた者の感情を 読み取れるようになった。
The box was made recently.
こ奴の余へ向けられた ただならぬ敵意もな。
The statue is rough and doesn't
adhere to any theme. I'd say it's only worth 1,500 Jenny.
な…　なんと
But there is a little aura...
一度　余の 「円」にさらされた者の心は
However, that would be its
appraisal as an artwork.
目を凝らすだけで　よく見えるわ。
The wood itself is quite valuable.
ユピーの翼や砲撃のみならず
So I'll make you an offer.
私の 「スピリチュアルメッセージ」も
If you sell me the painting
and doll for 420,000, I'll buy the wood for 80,000.
より高い次元の能力として 見事に昇華されている
A total of 500,000? What do you think?
クッ…
Feel free to think it over.
王！ 王は無敵！
But I doubt anyone will quote
you a better price.
王は無二！ なのに…
In the meantime, let me
check this wood's age. Wait!
なぜに！
Put down that statue.
言いようのない不安が 満たされて行くのでしょう？
He's offering a fair price
for the painting and doll, but he's lying about the statue! I-I never lied!
波のように寄せる 余への強い殺意は隠しようもない。
No collector would pay
80,000 for that wood. You're interested in the contents of that statue!
申してみよ　偽りは許さぬ。 うっ！
It's a wooden trove. A wooden trove? Three hundred years ago, these were a popular way for the
wealthy to hide their money.
感情に流されている 場合ではない！
To hide their money...
ありのままを。
If it's real, there should be valuables inside.
メルエム様！
You planned to steal the contents,
while pretending to check its age!
手順違いにございます。
I-I would never do that...
その者は 私の秘密に深くかかわる者。
But that only tells us the material's age. The statue itself could be modern.
しかし　それを自覚せぬ者。
This technique is known as hoodwinking, boys.
ん!?　ん!?
Technique?
図らずも　その者の口から 私の秘め事の一部
He's referring to a counterfeiter trying
to trick a professional appraiser. But that isn't what I'm doing.
もしくは全てが漏れることも 十分あり得まする。
Here's a seam that an amateur would never recognize. The seam contains an adhesive
王の能力を前にして
used back in that period.
うそは無力　ならば真実で！
You're insisting this is a real wooden trove?
勝敗を決する前に 戦利品の中身を知るは 王の本意と真逆でございましょう。
Yeah. But it is possible that it was opened
once to swap out its contents, and the statue was reassembled.
真実のみで ごまかしてみせる！
We'd call that a dud.
私との勝負 継続を　お望みならば その者との質疑 何とぞ　後回しにされますよう。
It's called double-dipping, placing new adhesive on top
of the old to create a dud.
こいつは一体 何　言ってやがる？
But only an amateur would try that.
秘密…　何のことだ？
A professional would melt
the adhesive with a flame, before resealing it.
いや　それよりも この場をどうする？ どうすれば　逃げ切れる？
That way, it would appear as though
the statue had never been opened.
この怪物から！
That's known as welding.
チクショ　まさか　こんな ばかげた化け物だとは！ さっさと逃げりゃ よかったんだ
It hasn't been welded. If fire were used, the wood would be scarred
or the adhesive would have discolored.
魔が差したんだ　クソ！
Even the pros have a hard time
weighing those details.
目の前で あんなに強大だったユピーが
I can't trust you.
ちっぽけな虫くずみてぇに あっさり　くたばりやがるから
I'm a pro appraiser! I swear by my eyes...
何か　俺でも王を やれるんじゃねえかみてぇに
This is a real wooden trove!
錯覚しちまった 残っちまった 酔っちまったんだ！
It's never been opened, and the treasure inside
hasn't been swapped out!
そうだ　バカだ俺は！ 酔ってたんだ俺は！ いろいろ一遍に起きて ジャイロのこと思い出して
Okay, let's assume that this is a
genuine wooden trove. If the contents have been swapped out, what would you do?
パニクって　センチになって ヒロイズムに酔っちまったんだ！ ジャイロのあだ討ちみてぇな 気分になって
I'll be your slave for the rest of my life.
ジャイロは死んじゃいねえのに きっと生きてるのに こっから逃げて また一緒につるんで
Give up.
感情を狂わせやがった 俺のレールを 変えやがったんだ
Wow! Awesome!
クソったれ 何がメッセンジャーだ！ 何とかしねえと…
Oh, so you're Zepile.
俺の敵意もバレてる うそは通用しねえ
Thanks, Zepile-san. You don't need to thank me.
「ミサイルマン」は発動させる前に 俺の首が消し飛ぶだろう！
Consider it give and take. Twenty percent sounds fair. Huh?
何が残ってる？　俺の手駒に
My cut when you sell the treasure. What?
メッセージ？　プフの秘密？
You're going to rob us?! That's uncalled for.
俺の感情の根源？
It's my fee for providing advice.
これを総動員して　俺は…
I don't see a problem.
一体　助かるのか？ 何を言えば？
He helped us back there. Now, look here...
最初の… 初めの　ひと言が勝負だ
We need to collect as much
Jenny as we possibly can. I might be willing to buy him lunch.
生死を分かつ 一世一代のひと言
Really? Then I'll settle for that.
間違えたら　その瞬間 全部　終わるかもしれねえ！
Huh? So, Zepile-san...
プフ　その秘密
In return, just tell me something. What tipped you off to bid on these items?
そ奴が余に向ける憎悪と わずかでも…。
Is it okay to tell him the truth?
かかわりがあると申すか？ これが王…
Well, it beats paying him. I see, Nen aura...
余を遮り　言葉尻を捉えた揚げ句 指図まがいの進言。
If you're telling the truth, that explains why you bought the statue, not realizing something was hidden inside.
よほどの覚悟の上であろう。
So, why do you need money so badly?
心して答えよ。
We can answer that question,
but not for free. Afterwards, you have to answer our question.
これは…
Sure, that's fine.
王の新たな能力は プフの返答を待つまでもなく
There's an item we want
to buy at the auction. That's why we need money.
是非の判定を可能としている
Oh, which item are you interested in? It's our turn now.
プフの 絶対的心服を知りつつなお
You estimated that this treasure
was worth 300 million, right?
まがまがしく明瞭に発せられる 殺意にまみれたオーラは
Could we receive that much
at the trade market?
是非にかかわらず　その答えが 王の意にそぐわぬ場合
At the trade market? They mainly deal in hard cash...
死をもって償う他ないことを 示していた
If you show up abruptly,
you won't get a fair price. What?
忠義も　敵意も
Seriously? Now it's my turn.
王の前では　皆　平等に無価値
I'll repeat the question. Which item do you want?
誰も止められない
A game called Greed Island. Oh, that ridiculously expensive game?
私は
How much is that weird pot
that you bought worth?
あの時
Huh? This? It's garbage.
すでに死を覚悟した身
Nothing at all.
殉じよう
Why do you want that expensive game? I believe it costs 6 billion?
己の忠義に
The asking price is 8.9 billion. We're looking for his dad.
何も申し上げるわけには まいりません。
That game has a clue inside. Oh... Why did you choose that pot?
勝負の途中　故。
If you knew the wooden trove was real, shouldn't you have bid on
the more valuable item?
ただ　それだけのこと
But you went for the pot. Why?
常軌を逸する決意　狂気が…
But it wasn't an original creation. It was a replica. In other words, a counterfeit.
王を止めた
Once I became an appraiser
and began earning money, I quit doing that.
腹が　へったな。 しかし…
When I see how poorly these are made, I feel mortified! So I browse the markets and buy them back.
ヒィ！
How much would a real one cost?
ウェルフィンは 即座に理解した
It's my turn. What does your dad do?
俺は…
He's a pro Hunter.
俺は食われて死ぬ！
How much would a real one cost?! Forty to fifty thousand.
およそ１秒先
There are a few in the antiques world, and not one of them is ordinary.
死ぬ！
Won't it be impossible for you
two to find him alone?
自身の未来を知った ウェルフィンの風貌は
It'll be fine.
I'm a pro Hunter, too. Huh? Seriously?
一瞬にして　１００年余りが 過ぎたかのごとく変わり果てた
Okay, your turn to ask a question.
生きたい！
Okay, this is my final question.
その間　脳裏では 過去の一切が高速で雑然と流れ
Can I help you with anything? Huh? If you want to make money at an auction,
you'll need an appraiser.
その直後　はじけ散り 現在と混ざり合った ひと言！
You could even say that with an appraiser, you can always turn a profit.
最初の！
You can set the price you want to pay me.
最期の！
How's that?
生への執着と 不可避の死との境界で
Then you have to answer our last question.
ひと言　メッセージ！
Why do you want to help us?
王との　ひと言！
Because it made me happy...
あの時　プフがピトーと ひと言！
It made me happy that this piece of junk actually caught your eye.
プフの秘密　ひと言！
It's not a piece of junk!
俺は　ひと言
It definitely holds your Nen.
死ぬまでは死なねえ!!
Everyone has some aura...
かつてなく　目まぐるしく働いた 脳細胞が導き出したのは
But it's incredibly difficult to harness!
通常であれば 選択し得ないものだった
You must concentrate and
train for a very long time. I can tell how much effort you
put into making that pot!
コムギ？
I still think it's a weird pot, though.
こ…　これほどとは…
That isn't important at all! But they sound fun!
Like magic tricks! We're not here to have fun!
プフ。
When I admitted to making forgeries
これが　其のほうの…。 はい。
and when that trader gave me a hard time... He didn't react with accusatory glares
何なりと処罰を。
or by plotting his own evil deeds. His reaction was very simple.
我らは異体同心　とがなどない。
Which means that he's dangerous...
かなうはずなどない
Someone who can never truly be appraised.
引き続き　ピトーを捜せ。 捕らえた２名が 何か知っているかもしれぬ。
Welding is the hardest
technique to see through.
聞き出せたら解放してやれ。 そ奴らに聞きたいことは もう　ない。
But recently, a new technique has surfaced. It's known as exposing.
うなずく他　あろうはずもない
You plainly reveal the opened statue
はっ…。
along with a fake treasure.
開いた扉　奥へ続く足跡 「円」で触れた２名の覚悟
Because people assume that you wouldn't open the statue
if the treasure were fake, you can fool them.
全てが一つの解を指している
But now this technique is getting old.
ウェルフィン。
When people started to get suspicious,
a new technique emerged.
はっ！　はい！ コムギは 地下格納庫のどこかに
Can you guess what it is? I know.
女とタコと共にいる。
The treasure inside is also fake!
お主は　それを 余か護衛軍に知らせる役目。
Wrong! I know!
な…　なぜ　それを！
Remove the treasure from a different place!
お主が役目を引き受けた 理由のカギは
Bingo!
タコにありそうだが 役目を全うしなかった理由は また　別。
You can create a new opening
and remove the treasure, then insert the fake
treasure and seal the hole.
それは　余への憎悪の根源に 起因するか？
This is known as side-stepping. Side-stepping...
図星か。
Many veteran appraisers have been fooled.
安心せい。 答えた後は　どこへ行こうと お主の自由だ。
They assume the statue is real if the
adhesive hasn't changed color from the application of fire.
礼を言う。
That's how they fool the pros.
お主のおかげで 大切なものを思い出せた。
You live in an incredible world.
うぅ…。
Hello?
奴らは Ｄエリアのビゼフ私庭で待つと。
What? A spider? Yeah, this looks real. There's a video attached.
うぅ…！
A man and a woman. I'll leave now, so let's meet there.
貴様は　貴様らは
Let's go, Killua. Yeah.
敵だ！　俺達の！
Hey! What about the auction?
さようか。
We'll let you handle it! Try to get us a good price!
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
Huh?
会えるといいな　その者と。 そして　可能なら
Okay! I've got it covered!
人として生きるがよい。 うっ　うぅ…！
Gon and Killua have learned
about a whole new world.